Okay, it looks like we are at the hour,
so I will just go ahead
and get started then.
So thank you all so much for joining
the storyboarding for Scrollimation Workshop,
and I'm really excited to have you here
and share a little bit about my passion
and process
for creating a School Nation
with all of you.
So just for anyone who
may have come in just now.
Yeah,
you should create an account
in order to do this,
and you should have an idea for a text
or story ready.
And for the workshop portion of paper and
pencil or digital drawing design program,
I will not be going into detail on how to
use scroll cinema during this workshop.
This is more about the process
or how to storyboard Forest Grill Cinema,
and we'll just dive right into the tool
when it comes time.
And just a bit about what
we'll be doing today.
First, I'll give a conceptual overview
of what this workshop is all about.
Anyone dedicate most of the time
actually to workshop activities.
I hope to get through two of them,
including brainstorming
and actually implementation
of our storyboards and prototypes.
And hopefully we have enough time
for project sharing as well.
Looks like we have a small group,
so we should be able to talk
through some things regarding school
and really excited for that.
So a little bit first on why?
Why have this workshop.
So seeing the experiences
of early users on
Alt Salt using Scroll Cinema,
I realized that folks could benefit
from a methodology
to more easily develop their skills.
Also,
there are technical considerations
that if you approach them strategically,
using school cinema will make the process
of creating schools much more fun
and productive, as well
as ultimately result in a better content.
So you may have also realized yourself
while using scroll
cinema that you could benefit
from from structure and planning.
So that's what this
this workshop is all about.
And importantly,
I think that these concepts translate
to creating interactive content
in general
and scrolling experiences
outside of just scroll cinema.
So that is something,
something you should be able to take
with you to other places as well.
And so to narrow down on our workshop
goals, then our primary goal is to
familiarize yourself with the importance
of creating interactive prototypes.
Very early on in the process
of creating scrolling.
And number two,
secondary goal is to actually block out
a full interactive prototype
of at least a segment of our stories.
So those are our workshop tools.
Some additional preparatory notes.
There's a key assumption
that I'm making here is that
we are aiming to create
engaging user experiences.
So this is a means engagement
over the concept.
And this is a process that I've come to
after spending a lot of time
working on projects that really didn't
ultimately live up to my standards
for engaging user experiences.
So that being said, I'm
still learning what works and figuring out
how to show this to others.
And it's my first time
teaching this workshop,
so it will be a learning experience
for all of us.
And ultimately,
I'm aiming to save you lots of time
and hard lessons
that I learned along the way.
And to go a little
bit more on the
the why and the theory behind this.
So school is an interactive format.
Therefore, to create engaging scrolls,
we should prototype early and create
an interactive skeleton
as early as possible to ensure our pieces
work on the mechanical level.
That is, if your piece doesn't work
when a person is scrolling
through it, experiencing it,
it doesn't matter how good the writing is,
it doesn't matter how good the images are.
Anything else.
If it just doesn't work at that mechanical
level, it's going to really prevent
people from being able
to immerse themselves in your story.
So that being said, once we have this
broad skeleton in place, if we do it
strategically, the skeleton also allows us
to easily iterate on our pieces,
adjusting the pacing and broad strokes,
and we gradually fill in the details
while always ensuring
that the piece in the macro works already.
So, and importantly,
the prototype will also allow us to test
working or not.
And in the process of testing
our own prototypes, that will also suggest
to us or bring ideas in mind on how
we can approach during the emotional beats
and is helpful
in the process of iteration.
So all in all, there are many reasons
why you want this storyboard and prototype
or scroll before we just dive right in.
And so
yeah, these are some of the
these are some of the reasons
and the little bit
about my typical process.
When I create a scroll, I typically go
from concept to script, storyboard often
on paper, then prototype in scroll cinema,
and then I iterate.
For today's focus,
we're going to skip the scripting aspect,
because I think it's really only possible
to script ahead of time.
If you have a solid idea of what scrolling
can do and possibilities there.
So yeah, I think we will be focusing
on concept, storyboard and prototype,
and hopefully we will be able
to get through all of that.
And so just a little bit more theory
before
we start going into
actually getting our hands dirty.
When we start with the concept phase,
whatever our story is,
and I want you to be thinking
about your story as I talk about this.
We want to be trying
to find those emotional beats.
Those, yeah, the emotions
that are at the core of our story.
Because Scroll Nation works
when the structure
is tied to a particular emotion or concept
we're trying to convey.
And so let's use
all the tools that are disposable
text, images, sound design, interactivity,
and make editorial choices about what
things we're going to use
and what mediums we're going to pull
from when we want to express
these emotional beads.
Okay.
And so I have a couple of examples
to show here,
so that this can be a bit more concrete.
Can never hear that sound.
Let me know.
Yes. Perfect okay.
So this is a piece called
when I Fall Asleep.
It's a comic
that I'm currently developing.
I don't know that all of it
is entirely successful, but I want to work
through some of the editorial choices
I made in making this.
I'm going to actually
turn down the volumes a little bit.
Okay, so from the beginning
we have a start button with this animation
to let folks know that this is,
you know, an experience
with some kind of a
visual interest happening. Right.
And then I really wanted to set
a reflective and introspective atmosphere
in this opening here.
So we're transitioning from these images
using this, these cross fades,
which is a little
plus a little thing that we wouldn't have
if we were making a normal webcomic.
Here I have this frame by frame
animation here just to set up
this contemplation, but it's not.
I just have the keyframes
or I don't have all the in-betweens.
Again, I'm trying to evoke this atmosphere
in a particular way,
and then we go from this day time to this,
darker toned
atmosphere with all of these
phosphor phobic images
really trying to set up the
the busyness of her morning routine
and how just the hamper she feels.
Right.
We have a moment of
of to take a breath here when she's
looking out the window of the bus.
And here we're going through her workday
in the office.
And then I want to pull your attention
to this part
right here, where we do a cross fade right
into the next morning.
So I wanted to compress the time here.
And this is one way
that I thought to do it.
I really wanted to emphasize
the repetitiveness,
the repetitive nature of her morning
routine. Right.
And you'll notice here
that before we go into the
we hear the sounds of traffic
before we actually see the cars, right?
To kind of set the tone
or set the idea that she's already
thinking about the stop the sound here,
she's already thinking about the traffic
before she even arrives.
Right.
And so in all
and it goes on a little bit more.
But in all, what I want to highlight here
is that I'm constantly thinking
about the internal
emotional state of the character
and then using the language of comics,
because I wanted this to be a webcomic,
but then also like the sounds
and the transitions, which are the things
that scrolling gives us to really put us
into the emotional state of the character.
So that is one example
from a piece in progress
of when I Fall Asleep With a friend.
I also ran through a part of
this workshop.
So this is a
vampire romance story, and
in this piece we were trying to analyze,
okay, what's the core emotional beat here?
And this is when the protagonist meets
the love interest for the first time.
Right?
And there is this emotional connection
between them.
And she,
not being an artist was thinking, okay,
how can we do this without images?
Given that the other examples like a full
webcomic, how else can you explore this?
Right?
And so we brainstormed
a bit and came up with this idea, right.
That there could be like these
two columns,
right where we can see their dialog
going back and forth
to emphasize the connection
between these characters.
Right.
And then Italian politics,
for anyone who doesn't speak Italian.
Right.
But this is just talking about how, like,
the vampire needs blood
and he's talking about, okay.
How can we some potential ways
to resolve that.
Right.
And here she is voicing
a thought inside her in the parentheses
while he is speaking.
Right.
And so this is just a nice way to
see this dynamic between these characters
and explore their internal thoughts
while they have this dialog in parallel,
without while also using
some nice treatment of text and such.
So keep the reader's interest.
So that's a little bit
on emotional beats.
And I yeah, would encourage you
to be thinking in the same way.
What are the emotional beats in my story,
and how can I use scroll
to really bring out those emotional beats
to help me make these editorial choices?
Okay, so that is that.
And just to give you a few more ideas
as well, I'm going to show you
some example templates,
which you can also download and import
directly into Scroll Cinema when it comes
to the second part of the workshop.
So I'll just show these really quickly
so you can have an idea.
As we move into the first exercise,
some things that you can do when it comes
to storyboarding your own piece.
So this is a template for a webcomic
more or less.
I've used just placeholder boxes to
to show what this could look like.
There is a small crossfade transition
between first page and the second page,
so that is a template for a webcomic.
We also have
this two column dialog
from a motor of amputee,
with all of the original content
stripped out.
So that is another sort of structure
you could use.
Here's an interesting one.
This is cross fading between images
right as we scroll.
So if you're thinking about
some kind of frame by frame animation
or what have you, this is another thing
that you can play with another idea.
Here's a vertical text template
if you want to have your text appear
in this way for an editorial reason,
that's something else to think about.
And here's another one
with the text moving
and the horizontal direction.
Right.
And this, I think, illustrates
a bit of the breadth that you can get
when you're thinking
about scrolling animations
and the different techniques
you can think about when applying
through your own stories.
So our goal at the end of this
workshop is for everyone here
to block out their own story in this way,
either using one of these templates
or ideally creating
your own your own structure.
So that is that.
And right
before we dive into the first activity,
remember a core principle
is that in scrolling,
pacing is the foundational parameter
that makes a piece successful.
So when you have your story idea
or your text, rather than thinking about
just reproducing it and scroll down,
maybe even copying word for word
into the scrolling,
let's think about really how to adapt
our stories and concept to the medium.
Do we change the text?
Do we introduce images instead?
Really, how can we
create an engaging user experience
and make that pacing successful?
Yeah, we're not doing a regular story.
We're making a scrolling. Right.
So let's really think, how can we
adapt our stories to make it engaging?
Okay.
And with that, that is all the theory
that we need to get started.
So for the first workshop activity,
let's find an emotional beat and thumbnail
or sketch.
A treatment for that
emotion will be in our story
on paper or using a digital program.
And I'll encourage you to use every tool
you have at your disposal.
This is and include stage notes in the
on the storyboard if you'd like.
So this includes sounds, interactions,
what should be animated, etc.
and I would.
I strongly encourage you to not worry
about feasibility for this exercise.
I really want you to use
this as an exercise to think of
what's possible with the medium, right?
So if you can't animate,
just include animations.
You know, if you can't draw images,
just include that what have you right.
And just feel free
to let your mind run wild.
And so yes, I think I can stop.
Maybe I won't stop sharing,
but I'd like to stop over into the chat
and see how folks are going, and
I can set up a timer for a few minutes.
Are there any questions so far?
I really.
Oh, here we go.
I can see everyone now.
Let me go.
So the timer
how about we start with ten minutes?
And I'll go ahead and.
Start drawing some things out myself.
And there's everyone have as everyone goes
as I won't have their paper and pencils
ready or their digital program.
Is anyone missing a story?
If anyone has any clarifying details,
feel also free to let me know.
I just wanted
to make sure you saw the question in chat.
Yep, I'm responding right now.
Yeah, I forgot that I can respond,
you know, with my real voice.
Yeah.
So if you look at the workshop folder,
there is a folder for templates in there.
You can just download those.
And if you go to Alt
Salt and into the editor,
this is the next exercise by the way.
This is the activity tool
will actually implement the our storyboard
incentive scroll cinema.
If you go to the import
button up here in the top left,
you should be able to import your scroll
scroll cinema project file. So.
So I'll go over that.
I'll show you how to do that
in the next exercise as well.
One minute mark, one minute mark,
and then we'll pick one
one enthusiastic participant to share.
It doesn't need to be perfect,
just needs to be
a small slice
and attempt trying to think through.
Storyboarding your skill. 20s.
So that is the ten minute mark.
I know a very small amount of time
to storyboard something, but this is more
to learn about the process than it is
to actually finish the whole thing.
How did it go, and do
we have any brave soul willing to talk us
through at least a small piece
of their storyboard for two minutes or so?
Any takers?
Did I pick someone at random?
Would you be willing?
Well,
I have a very clear
concept of what I want to do and
and is inspired also by the way,
that all the possibilities
of of this program and is based on
its poetry. Right.
So there is a process.
So you want me to share
just the concept in the specific concept.
So, so what I want to use
is this the poetry,
along with images related to some of the
and there is a narrative there.
So there is a process.
So I would like to use the images
and the sound and the
and the poetry to,
to keep going in that process.
So yeah, I very, I have a very clear
idea of what I'd like to do. Yes.
Okay. Cool.
And and just so that is one approach
and I'll just go here
and show a quick storyboard that I did on
break through this exercise yesterday.
I'm not sure if it's possible to see this.
Maybe.
No, no.
Okay.
So I think we can just get that done.
But yeah, but basically I just
it was a story about the folklore,
folkloric story
about a llama from the Andes.
And I just sketched out some images
and some treatment of how that could,
what that could look like
with the images coming in with the sounds
and things like that.
And so,
so yeah, that was the first activity.
Okay.
So now that we all have our storyboards,
our some idea of what
we want to implement,
the next step is to build a robust
skeleton inside of scroll seminar cinema
that is interactive, that will allow us
to get an idea of the pacing
and the the mechanics of our story
at the macro level.
So what we're going to do
is we're going to create
placeholder blocks for our content
and organize them into logical groups.
And some rules of thumb here
for scrolling groups
should definitely generally
move 1920 pixels for every 1.7 seconds,
and horizontal scrolling
1080 pixels for every .56 seconds.
I'll show you what that means.
Right now, I also show you how
to implement some of these,
how to
import these scroll cinema templates
so you can have something to start with
if you'd like.
So I'm going to implement
import the webcomic template.
So I just want to import
I have the template downloaded
from the from the project folder.
It takes a couple of seconds
and once it imports I have this.
I have this template in front of me.
I'm going to go to the timeline here
in the bottom left and select the main
reel, and I'm going to scrub through
and see the content here.
Okay.
So one key thing to notice is that I
have these I have this
project grouped into two pages.
And let me move my talking
head out of the way here.
Let me minimize the meeting chat.
So you'll see that
we start out at position zero zero.
And then we move over here at the 3.4
second mark
to 1000 or 3840.
So, there's some details as to why
1920 pixels or vertical screen length.
We do that for every 1.7 seconds.
But just think of it
as a good rule of thumb.
So here at the 1.7 mark
where at 1920 pixels,
and then I realized I wanted more like
we were at the end of this page,
but then I wanted to take it off
the screen, right? So
to take it off the screen I set,
I moved the keyframe to 3.4 seconds,
and then I modify the
the position to let me minimize this here.
Then I change the position to 3840.
Right.
And so.
That moves that off the page.
And then right as that one's
moving off the page, I have page two
right which starts out here
off screen -1920.
And then as page
one is moving off the page
I move on page two onto the screen.
Right.
And so at 1.7 seconds from when it starts
animating which will be 3.1.
It's a little off
because we're interpolating here,
but it's at about zero, right?
And then
once I want as I want to keep moving it
off, keep moving it
every 1.7 seconds, I'll move it
1920 pixels until
it gets to where I want it to be.
Right.
So that's just a good rule of thumb.
You can play with it.
But the reason we do that is that as
we break our story into these sections,
we can imagine we'll have like several
pages, five, 6 or 7 pages going at once.
So if we create this project skeleton,
then that means if we want to adjust
the pacing and say page two,
we can adjust page
two and very easily move the
move the animation of the
page so that we are only modifying
that one section.
Right.
And so in that way, that allows us to
gradually manipulate
each section of the project
without affecting the other ones, and
just allows us to be more robust, right,
in our handling of everything.
So I can answer more questions on that,
if you like, if anything was unclear.
But yeah, that is a rule of thumb
for creating a scroll cinema.
You have your storyboard tried
to think about where can I block this out?
What things can they group together
and move and sync and
and and yeah,
that's the be thinking about that.
I also want to show the horizontal.
The horizontal approach.
Just to give you an idea of that for anyone who is doing something horizontally.
Has the same idea here.
The the width is 1080 pixels.
So every .56 seconds
we're going to move 1080 pixels.
And,
and just keep that as a rule of thumb.
And generally I will say for example
start out with at .56 I'll move it
1080 pixels
say, okay, it didn't move far enough,
I need to keep moving it.
And I'll just, you know,
keep adding screen links.
Right.
With that general rule of thumb
until I get to where I need it to be.
And this is just a place to start out.
After that, you can adjust further
to get the pacing that you like.
Okay. So
that is a little bit on that.
And so our workshop activity number two
then is using a template.
We're starting from scratch.
I'd like you to block out your storyboard
using Scroll Cinema.
So use your
The Shape tool to create gray blocks.
If you've made any sketch or what
have you,
you can import that in the school system
and you can use that.
Use placeholder text.
We're trying to do
is get a skeleton of our project with out
any even content finalized in it,
just so we can scroll through it
and see what the pacing is like.
Okay.
And let me open up the chat
and see our participants
and see if there are any questions.
I may have to turn my blur off.
Yeah,
we're folks unable to see the
oh oh for the the storyboard.
Okay, I got that. The yeah, it's
all right.
We don't need to
we don't need to see my see my sketches.
We can just dive right into the tool.
So please, anyone let me know
if you have any questions with the tool.
Let's give let's start out
with another ten minutes for this.
And we can see how folks are doing.
Maybe add a few 3 to 5 minutes after that,
and then maybe spend
a few times going through the prototypes
that folks have created
that I think would be
would be excellent.
Okay.
Yeah. Great.
Patrick, great to have you here.
First experience with scrolling.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm really, really glad you're
interested. Yes.
Feel free to.
Even if it's your first experience
with still feel free to to import
one of the templates
and just play around with it
and fill in your own content and
click the preview button.
Scroll through it, you know.
Yeah,
it could be a good way to get started.
It looks like we had a few people
just join us.
We are
currently in Workshop activity number two
where we are
implementing our storyboards
in Scroll Cinema.
If you're just arriving here,
I'll paste the workshop folder here.
Again.
If you're just arriving
you can go to this workshop folder.
Find all the slides
there as well as some scrolling templates.
You can download the scrolling templates
and import them right into Scroll Cinema
by logging to your also account.
Going to add new scrolling?
I'll show that really quick.
Go into your account.
Going to add new scrolling.
And clicking the import
button and selecting your selecting
the templates you like to play with,
and all the links to the various templates
so you can see what they are are in the
example template.
Slide in the
in the slides.
And actually
I'm going to I'm going to block out my
my magic llama story while.
With all of you
while we're doing this.
Just to go along.
I've got a question.
Is there is there an invitation code
or what not to get into Scroll Nation?
Nope. No invitation because right now,
yeah, you can just log in,
create an account and.
Oh okay. Great.
You can get get right in okay.
Because it's saying like early access
and whatnot.
Oh yeah. Yeah, yeah.
We're on the whole platform
and are in early access right now.
Okay. Yeah.
That's just, you know, give the heads up.
Things are still in progress. Right.
We're not a 1.0 issue yet.
Okay? You're having issues.
I don't know why I don't need to apply
to get in.
Do I know. No.
It's a yeah. It's open access right now.
Okay. Cool. Okay. Great. Yes.
Yeah I downloaded the the templates.
I tried to import them, but it didn't.
It didn't allow me to import it
in outsold.
I don't know what I did.
Yeah sure.
Yeah. Show me your screen
if you're comfortable.
Let me see. Yeah, sure.
Let me see.
Can you see that?
Can you see me?
Okay.
I can see your screen now.
Yes, yes.
Okay, so this is this is my thing.
And when I try to import it.
Then I use the.
Here are the imported files.
Not they are not showing.
Oh, try, try try downloading them
individually.
Oh, no. Why do they call.
Why is there a zip
at the end of them change.
I don't know why.
To them get rid
of the zip and they should
the files themselves.
That's strange. Rename or something?
That's it.
Okay. No.
Go to your try.
Try downloading the template
that you like individually.
It looks like it added zip
for something to it
instead of.
Okay, sorry about that.
No, no. Thank you. This is amazing.
It's really brilliant.
This program I love it.
Okay, I'll try that
I don't I'm going to stop sharing the.
Okay okay.
Question
about adding elements to the panel.
We have a chance. Yes.
Alex, feel free to ask your question.
Share my screen.
Okay.
Yeah.
So I didn't start from a template.
So that might be my first.
But I
yeah.
So I don't I have these four text nodes.
How do you actually get them
into the timeline okay.
So press the in the project tab
you'll see the second button
which looks like a film strip.
Press that and they'll create a real
gotcha scroll one.
Yeah.
And what is time and manual also.
So a scroll real will advance
space and swipe input.
A time will advance
based on the system clock.
So it's just a regular animation
that plays by itself.
And then manual reels are ones
that are triggered by user
input programmatically. Right.
But for the time in the manual
a little bit more advanced.
So just stick with the default
settings on the scroll.
And in the in the bottom left where
it says select sequence, select me real.
And then if you go up to your text nodes
now click on one of them.
You'll see that the K or keyframes
button has been activated.
So if you press that you'll be able to
start animating any of those properties.
So yeah,
for the storyboarding thing
we're trying to block out experiences,
but you can just have fun animating
if you'd like.
If you'd like to block things out,
you can also group everything
into a group
and then animate the group. So.
Gotcha. Cool.
Yeah, I'm sure you taught all this
in the previous workshop.
So sorry for. Yeah, yeah, no. No problem.
I really appreciate the storyboarding
tips to.
I'm actually I'm working on some moving
text animation toolkits in my own.
And this is
I like how fully feature this seems.
I mean, I'm going to be teaching a class
on moving text and I'm like
wondering
if I should teach with this stuff.
Oh please do.
Yeah.
We had Paula from Wayne
State University was one teacher
he used the last semester.
And yeah,
they seemed to have a good time with it.
He's planning on making it a mandatory
part of his course for next semester.
So that's what we have in
for plans so far.
And there's been some cool student work
done with it.
So yeah,
if you'd like to talk more about that too,
please let me know
and we can get you all set up. And
so yeah, I'd love to keep talking.
This is yeah, this is super cool
I wait, so sorry.
So I have this okay. So I have this.
Now I just need to keyframe it.
Oh here I see that okay.
So this okay I'll play with this.
Thank you. Move the scrubber.
Move the scrubber from the zero position
to like some point
at some point in the future.
And then yeah you can add a new keyframe
or just move the box.
Move the text box.
It'll automatically create a new keyframe
when you change the position.
A super cool. Okay.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I see so now.
So if I wanted someone
to appear at this keyframe,
I would say like.
Okay,
how are we all doing with blocking out
our scrolling more time?
Tina is the only person
whose face I can see.
But how are you doing? Tina,
any more time?
Yes, yes, I have some some problems.
I the only thing now is
sorry is when I try to import it
says this will delete all existing assets
and replace all projects data.
Yeah.
So I say yes okay.
But then I don't I cannot
sorry I need to
I need to play with this
because obviously it's not working.
I don't see the, the specific template
just a white space.
Here.
Show me to share your screen again. Yes.
Yeah. Tested all this before.
Before running.
Maybe there's some need to look into.
Yeah.
So if you click the
you need to select the timeline.
So in the bottom left
where it says select sequence.
Yes it's true.
Yes. Select me. Yeah. Yeah.
And so yeah.
So if you now to scrub
yeah yeah yeah okay.
Makes sense. Good.
Thank you I'll work on that.
Okay.
So yeah I think we'll put another
five minutes on the clock.
And then we can
maybe try sharing a little bit
of what folks have come up with
for the last few minutes.
Alex,
you can feel free to show your screen
and ask one question.
If no one else has any questions,
I can help you or Tina
or anyone else.
Yeah, I think I'm still
struggling to.
Know if I have keyframe this correctly,
I think I haven't.
Okay,
so let's say
just like just to make this appear
appear.
Do you mean like, like you want it to
start out passively zero
and go to a past one, perhaps?
Yeah, that would do it.
So I guess I would say
keyframe. Yeah.
Here,
take that down to zero.
Okay.
And then move it to say the one position
discovery.
Yeah.
And then move
scrub up to one or type one or something.
Yeah.
And now scrub it. Yeah. Yep.
Then to play the preview.
How do I do that.
Yeah. So save draft
and then press the preview button
in the top right.
Oh yep yep.
And scroll
cool okay.
Nice suites.
Thanks so much.
Yeah absolutely.
Everyone else is very quiet.
How are you all doing out there?
Good to see you, Zach.
Or good?
This is good to have you here.
And is it doing some kind of,
like tweaking by default?
Yes.
So it tweens between the positions.
Between the keyframes by default.
Yeah.
Looks like we had a couple of other
a couple of new folks join.
I just paste in the.
Pace in the workshop
folder again for everyone.
If you just read not too long ago,
we're running through the second exercise
of blocking out our experiences
in scroll cinema.
If you're just writing,
can maybe go into the workshop folder.
Download
these scroll cinema files individually.
Apparently,
downloading them all as a folder
doesn't work for some reason,
which I'll look into.
But yeah, if you download these template
files individually, you should be able
to import them into scroll cinema
by coming into the editor and import and
and selecting your template.
And the keyframe number
in the scroll case.
Does that correspond to like
what does that correspond to.
Is it
like how many widths you've scrolled.
You mean the x and the Y?
I guess it's so like in the like
if I'm looking at like one point.
Oh yeah. Up there is that.
Yeah. What does that correspond to.
Show me your screen.
Yeah.
I guess I'm just like asking.
So here I guess I'm just asking like this.
Does this mean that, like, we've scrolled
half of a bar or the.
Yeah. So so those are actually a seconds.
So the with scroll cinema.
Oh here let me.
Stop this timer.
Yeah.
So with scroll cinema
a big part of what we do is
we have a primary scrolling sequence,
but then we have time
based sequences that loop animations
and do other things right.
And at any moment
we also have these auto playing sequences
within scrolling sequences
that our time based.
Right.
So yeah, as we swipe
through its in user time,
but we often mix
like these user driven sequences
with these time based sequences.
So that's why everything is in seconds.
That makes sense.
But so is it
is the swiping kind of simulating
moving forward in time then.
Yeah.
So basically not simulating
it is actually moving forward in time.
So yeah, a conceptual thing with scroll
cinema
is that everything is just one
big animation.
The, the thing that we're doing is
we're creating the illusion
of scrolling by.
Yeah, moving things on
and off the stage.
But really, when we swipe, we're
just advancing an animation timeline.
But that becomes very flexible
because there's just a lot of things
you can do with that.
So yeah, that makes a lot of sense. Sweet.
Yeah.
Thanks for all the answering
all the new questions.
No, no. Yeah.
Thank you for being
here and for your interest.
Okay, so we have just a few minutes.
Would anyone like to screen
share their prototype
or maybe drop a link into what they have,
what they have created
so we can give it a shot?
I'm eager to see everyone scrolling.
Okay.
Looks like nothing. Let's see if I can.
If there's anything I can show here.
Yeah, that's the activity
through to share and browse
other participants creations.
I think we have some folks here
who have not seen
some of the student work and such
that has been created,
so maybe I'll just go ahead
and share some of that.
So let me share my screen.
So if you haven't yet seen the
The School publication,
there's a link to it on the homepage of
alt right now.
And this is a project
that or a discipline,
the medium that I'm championing
and really trying to get off the ground
because I think it's so much expressive
and creative potential.
So here's a piece by XT and burrow
featured in the collection.
Very interesting use
of just these gifts and animations, right?
So I really love that I showed you
an example of when I fall asleep.
Here's another.
This is a piece made by a student
which has a very different sensibility.
And I really love it's
just a small class exercise, but just.
I hadn't thought to do this right.
So I think that's really exciting.
And the use of the color palette
and whatnot.
Another piece
that I'm really excited about,
in fact, even exploring myself further,
this kind of
the style of scrolling
is also featured on the home page.
Again, for a class assignment,
it looks like they took
photos using their cell phone and just did
this beautiful frame by frame.
Sort of.
Yeah, just reminiscing about, like,
it seems like a summer or something
like that.
Anyway, I love this style.
And so that's
just a little bit of the breadth
that you can get out of cinema.
And of course, we didn't invent scrolling,
editorial landing pages
and other things like that.
But I think in terms of the creative side,
there's still so many things
that are left to be explored with skill,
and that I'm really excited to see
what you all come up with and all that.
I should also mention that
scroll scroll Mason is
not just scroll cinema right in the scroll
Mason publication, the first anthology
that we've come up with on
regarding civilization,
and I hope to have more in the future.
Here's a piece by Hayley Maddy,
for example, which is written
in his custom code.
And yeah, this is also a scroll, right?
It's not made using scroll cinema,
but this is
you know,
there's just a lot of things you can do
with this,
with these very simple ideas of scrolling.
And I think it solves
a lot of user experience issues
around electronic literature,
and is a nice gateway into creating
and experiencing
potentially a big commercial frontier.
Here's a piece by Jody Allen.
Again, this is a
not scroll cinema, but is another example
of just some very interesting, cool
visual things happening
all based around this idea of scrolling.
So I encourage
you to check this things out.
It looks like we have three minutes left.
Do we have any questions
before we wrap up?
I'm curious.
Yeah, I think this is awesome.
I agree that I feel like you've solved
some of the user
interface issues in terms of making,
but also consuming.
But I'm curious,
like the terms of exporting.
If you see this as mostly shared
through a,
through like a publication,
kind of like what is hosted right now
on on that front page
or if like support, it supports Instagram
like export into Instagram or video
or I guess you could just record your own
I suppose.
Also having made. Yeah.
So I see it as inherently interactive.
Maybe there's a way that we can
make videos and publish them on Instagram.
What have you.
But yeah, you can export the HTML
and post them anywhere.
I'm championing also is like a way
for folks to come together
to start building the community.
But yeah, you can take your skill
based on your where you'd like.
And yeah, I really see it
as a medium and discipline
that is with a lot of potential.
Maybe Facebook like support
for interactive things in the future,
so we'll see about that.
But yeah.
Thank you for the question.
And with that, I should start wrapping up.
Thank you all
so much for coming to this workshop.
You can
find the link to the discord
in the footer.
Also, you can subscribe to our newsletter
in the footer of alt
for updates and, you know,
sign up for your accounts as well
and let me know what you're creating.
There's my email address or com.
Anyway, I think this medium,
as I mentioned, is so much potential.
Love to see what you're making. Legacy
in your classrooms.
And yeah, let's make scroll happen.
Thank you so much for your time.